<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-01T13:50:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dana Lee Gibson</title><subtitle>This is a blog about Technology and Design but also about life.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Do Not Lock Clients Out!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/do-not-lock-clients-out/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do Not Lock Clients Out!" /><published>2018-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/do-not-lock-clients-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/do-not-lock-clients-out/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/angry-IT-guy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Locking out clients is a bad idea&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a developer I feel it is morally (&lt;em&gt;and legally&lt;/em&gt;) wrong to withhold information about a clients website or hosting. Why some developers take their anger or frustration out on their clients is beyond me. I fully understand how difficult some clients can be, but nothing they can do should make you abandon your own professionalism.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-professional-at-all-times&quot;&gt;Be Professional at all times!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not like it, but sometimes clients move on. You might feel that you’ve been taken advantage of, or that you have been unfairly treated. It can sometimes feel like someone is dumping you. Painful, and/or frustrating as it may be, no one should be able to make you abandon your professionalism. &lt;strong&gt;Only you can do that&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, your professionalism should be what supports you through difficult clients. After all, what is the point of offering client’s services if you are not going to do it correctly. When you run a business it is just as much about attitude as it is about quality of the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-you-owe-clients&quot;&gt;What do you owe clients?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You owe them everything!&lt;/strong&gt; By that I mean they should get everything. They should be given access to every service you create or manage for them. You are morally (and legally) obligated to make sure they have all the account names, URL’s and passwords for &lt;strong&gt;ALL&lt;/strong&gt; their sites and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see way too many “&lt;em&gt;developers&lt;/em&gt;” who, through either spite or laziness do not supply this vital information to their clients. Too many times I have had to hunt down and reset all kinds of information for clients because their original developer has flaked on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;as-a-client-what-should-i-have&quot;&gt;As a client, what should I have?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any developer you hire should supply you with everything! All the URL’s and all the passwords to everything should be given to you. All accounts, everything like hosting, or &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificates&lt;/strong&gt;, or any type of cloud service like &lt;strong&gt;CDN&lt;/strong&gt;, should ALL be setup using your email accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, and when you move away from your developer you need to be able to do two things. The first is gain access to all your services. The second is to change the passwords to all your services so the old developer no longer has access. This is to protect yourself as well as your old developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the relationship between you and your developer ends, it can get messy. Some people are not stable and may want to retaliate. Locking them out of your services protects you. It might sound strange but it protects the developer as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clients can be unstable as well, they can mess things up and then blame the old developer. As a developer, when a client leaves you, make sure it is a clean and total split. Do not get hung out to dry by a crazy client who might try to make you liable for something you didn’t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;things-happen-be-prepared&quot;&gt;Things Happen, Be Prepared!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is happening all the time. Things can happen that are out of the control of everyone. Making sure that a developer has shared all the important information with you (&lt;em&gt;as the client&lt;/em&gt;) is just good practice. If a developer becomes unavailable through no fault of their own, having this information will be vital to your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-the-bottom-line&quot;&gt;What is the bottom line?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a client, insist on being kept up-to-date by the developer. Tell them before you hire them this is what you expect from them. Make sure they understand you are to have all your usernames and passwords. Letting them know that you will retain master control over everything from the beginning will save a lot of trouble. Oh, and make sure you save all this information in a &lt;strong&gt;VERY safe place&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a developer, make sure you pass all data onto your client. Not just because it is the proper and professional thing to do. But because it makes the client feel more involved. It makes them feel safer, that they have control of things. It doesn’t matter that they have no idea what to do with the control. At the very least they will not feel held hostage by you. This will build good will with the clients. And you know what they say, happy clients, happy life. Or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-not-them-its-you&quot;&gt;Its not them, its you!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not trying to say all developers are flakes (&lt;em&gt;but a lot are&lt;/em&gt;). What I am saying is, &lt;strong&gt;protect yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. As a client make sure you can move forward without your current developer. As a developer make sure your client(s) can move forward without you. You may not like it, but as a professional developer that is part of your responsibilities to your clients.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="technology" /><category term="business" /><summary type="html">As a developer I feel it is morally (and legally) wrong to withhold information about a clients website or hosting. Why some developers take their anger or frustration out on their clients is beyond me. I fully understand how difficult some clients can be, but nothing they can do should make you abandon your own professionalism.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/angry-IT-guy.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Location, A Flasher Story</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/location-a-flasher-story/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Location, A Flasher Story" /><published>2018-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/location-a-flasher-story</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/location-a-flasher-story/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/Location-The-Flasher-Story.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Locating the Flasher Module on a 2000 Ford F150.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I use my blinker too &lt;strong&gt;much&lt;/strong&gt;? I don’t think I do. But then, much like being an &lt;strong&gt;asshole&lt;/strong&gt;, or truly crazy, self realization can be tricky. Asshole or not, I have had to replace the flasher module on both my &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebusabides.com&quot;&gt;Skoolie&lt;/a&gt;, as well as my 2000 Ford F150 pickup within the past &lt;strong&gt;30&lt;/strong&gt; days.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebusabides.com&quot;&gt;Skoolie&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt; so it’s failure could have been just to age. The blinkers didn’t totally fail on the bus. They began blinking like strobe lights. I was worried I was going to trigger seizures every time I made a turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ford F150 is a &lt;strong&gt;2000&lt;/strong&gt; so it does have a few years under it’s belt. With over 210,000 miles on it there are more then a few parts that have been replaced. However the blinker module is kind of an odd part to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;total-blinker-failure&quot;&gt;Total Blinker Failure!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blinkers stopped working, totally. Also the flashers would not work. When they first failed they come back to life for one or two turns before totally giving up the ghost. It wasn’t too hard to diagnose the problem. The fuse, (#13) on the fuse panel by the driver’s left knee was fine. That left just one culprit, the flasher module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say the choice of location for such a simple little device is beyond me. In my memory I do not recall a flasher module being any other place than either the fuse panel inside the car, or the fuse box under the hood. Imagine my surprise when I found out the dash will need to be disassembled!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-to-take-the-dash-apart&quot;&gt;Time To Take The Dash Apart!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/Dash-taken-apart.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-title=&quot;Image title&quot; data-footer=&quot;Image footer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/Dash-taken-apart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Taking the dash apart on a 2000 Ford F150&quot; width=&quot;960px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to remove the panel under the steering wheel, as well as the “&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;” shaped panel around the top and sides of the steering column. Then you have to remove a bracket that is located just above, and behind, the &lt;strong&gt;ODB&lt;/strong&gt; port. The flasher module is mounted on this bracket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/new-ford-flasher-module-installed.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-title=&quot;Image title&quot; data-footer=&quot;Image footer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/new-ford-flasher-module-installed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Remove the two bolts holding the bracket, it makes access to flasher module much easier.&quot; width=&quot;960px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a cover that must be removed. Then you can get to the &lt;strong&gt;$17.49&lt;/strong&gt; part (&lt;em&gt;NAPA part# NF EP27&lt;/em&gt;). Then you just unplug the old one and install the new one. Then it is time to reinstall the dash. For us that meant doing it two times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/Questioning-fords-flasher-location.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-title=&quot;Image title&quot; data-footer=&quot;Image footer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/Questioning-fords-flasher-location.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Why did Ford up the flasher module here?&quot; width=&quot;960px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time we got the dash together we realized we had forgotten to install the cap over the modules, and we had &lt;strong&gt;3 bolts leftover!&lt;/strong&gt; Removing it and putting it all back together a second time let us discover where those extra bolts went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure there was a lot of planning and engineering that went into figuring out the best location for this module. However, I clearly see three unused spaces on the fuse panel that would accept a flasher-type module. Why those slots were left empty is beyond me. After all the &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebusabides.com&quot;&gt;Skoolie&lt;/a&gt; flasher module was simple to find and replace, no tools required!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/School-bus-flasher-module-location.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-title=&quot;Image title&quot; data-footer=&quot;Image footer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/School-bus-flasher-module-location.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The 1995 International school bus has a much better flasher module location.&quot; width=&quot;960px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="technology" /><category term="story" /><summary type="html">Do I use my blinker too much? I don’t think I do. But then, much like being an asshole, or truly crazy, self realization can be tricky. Asshole or not, I have had to replace the flasher module on both my Skoolie, as well as my 2000 Ford F150 pickup within the past 30 days.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Location-The-Flasher-Story.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Too Much Choice?!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/there-is-too-much-choice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Too Much Choice?!" /><published>2017-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/there-is-too-much-choice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/there-is-too-much-choice/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/too-much-choice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Too much choice can led to sadness and buyer's remorse.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get asked all the time to be the arbiter of technology. People get overwhelmed with the volume of choices out there. And while choice and variety is good, it can sometimes be too much. After all, there is such a thing as too much of a good thing.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;name-that-tune&quot;&gt;Name That Tune!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets look at guitars. There are all sorts of guitars made for all sorts of music. But even if you stick to one style of music and one manufacture you are still faced with a mind numbing selection. Fender, an American institution since &lt;strong&gt;1950&lt;/strong&gt;, are also an ocean of choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/fender-stratocaster-choice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Want a Fender Stratocaster? There are lots to choose from.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fender.com&quot;&gt;Fender Stratocaster&lt;/a&gt;, but do you want an &lt;strong&gt;American&lt;/strong&gt; Stratocaster? It is made in the good-old &lt;strong&gt;US&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; and starts around &lt;strong&gt;$1200&lt;/strong&gt;. Or do you want a &lt;strong&gt;Mexican&lt;/strong&gt; Stratocaster, made in, you guessed it, Mexico. They start around &lt;strong&gt;$600&lt;/strong&gt;. Or do you want a Fender &lt;strong&gt;Squire&lt;/strong&gt; Stratocaster, which are made in Indonesia? Those start around &lt;strong&gt;$200&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t end there. Within each model based on area of manufacture there are different series and options to choose from. The rabbit hole goes far and deep!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are &lt;strong&gt;ALL&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fender.com&quot;&gt;Fender Stratocasters&lt;/a&gt;, they all look very similar, but are they the same? Sure, a &lt;strong&gt;$200&lt;/strong&gt; guitar is going to be different from a &lt;strong&gt;$1200&lt;/strong&gt; guitar. The problem isn’t that they are different, the problem is you will never be happy with your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;always-leaping-never-happy-where-you-land&quot;&gt;Always Leaping, Never Happy Where You Land&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies have shown the more choices a customer has, the more likely they are to suffer from buyer’s remorse. With so many guitars to choose from you’ll never know if you’ve chosen the best one. In the back of your mind you will know that you might have gotten a better one. If only you had spent more time looking, or if you had spent more money, or gotten different options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you had just two choices for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fender.com&quot;&gt;Fender Stratocaster&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;$1500&lt;/strong&gt; model or a &lt;strong&gt;$800&lt;/strong&gt; model you would get the one you could afford. You would be happy knowing you did the best you could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/danelectro-guitars.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Danelectro guitar offers real choice.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some guitar companies do this. &lt;a href=&quot;http://danelectro.com&quot;&gt;Danelectro guitars&lt;/a&gt; are not the most high-end instruments but they are very good. They have been making guitars since &lt;strong&gt;1954&lt;/strong&gt;. The company made guitars and amplifiers under contract that were branded with the names of various store brands, such as &lt;strong&gt;Silvertone&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Sears&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;Airline&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Montgomery Ward&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They don’t use exotic woods or come with hand crafted electronics. They are actually made out of Masonite and plywood. But who uses such a “&lt;em&gt;cheap&lt;/em&gt;” guitar? Well just people like, Glen Campbell, Elvis Costello, Jeff Beck, John Fogerty, Dave Mathews, George Harrison, Jimi Hendrix, and John Lee Hooker to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the &lt;a href=&quot;http://danelectro.com&quot;&gt;Danelectro guitars&lt;/a&gt; are manufactured in the same place, Korea (&lt;em&gt;they make very good guitars&lt;/em&gt;). The most expensive guitar they sell is about &lt;strong&gt;$800&lt;/strong&gt;, and the cheapest is about &lt;strong&gt;$350&lt;/strong&gt;. But that is for different types of guitars. Within a specific model (&lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt;) of guitar there are no “&lt;em&gt;versions&lt;/em&gt;”. The only option you get is color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means you know, for sure, you have gotten the &lt;strong&gt;BEST&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://danelectro.com&quot;&gt;Danelectro guitar&lt;/a&gt; you can get. You pick the type of guitar for the style of music you play and &lt;strong&gt;BOM!&lt;/strong&gt; Done, no buyer’s remorse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-a-computer-is-not-any-better&quot;&gt;Choosing A Computer is Not Any Better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/mac/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; is better than most, but they are still a bit of a nightmare. If you want a desktop computer you can either have the iMac or the Mac Mini. If you choose an iMac then you must choose iMac Pro or standard. If you choose the standard iMac then you have to choose size, &lt;strong&gt;21.5”&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;27”&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/iMac-big-or-smal-or-iMac-Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The choice of a iMac or iMac Pro is not that simple.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However there are three levels within either the &lt;strong&gt;21.5”&lt;/strong&gt; or the &lt;strong&gt;27”&lt;/strong&gt; iMac. And within each one of those you have choices to make. The problem is, beyond the type (&lt;em&gt;laptop or desktop&lt;/em&gt;) and the style (&lt;em&gt;Mini or all-in-one&lt;/em&gt;) the average person has no idea what to choose. What &lt;strong&gt;CPU&lt;/strong&gt; should you get? How much &lt;strong&gt;RAM&lt;/strong&gt; do you need? How much storage space should you have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-really-doesnt-matter&quot;&gt;It Really Doesn’t Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/mac/&quot;&gt;Apple products&lt;/a&gt; it really doesn’t matter. You can’t upgrade the machine after you buy it, so you had better get the &lt;strong&gt;MOST&lt;/strong&gt; of everything &lt;strong&gt;NOW&lt;/strong&gt;! The “&lt;em&gt;choice&lt;/em&gt;” they are giving you is an illusion. An illusion that does nothing but confuse people, even professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I “&lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt;” the &lt;strong&gt;i7&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;4.2GHz&lt;/strong&gt; CPU? For what I do, more then likely not. But a new iMac without it will quickly become obsolete. Do I need an American made Fender guitar? Not really but it will hold its value far more than a Mexican made, or an Indonesian Squire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fewer-choices-would-be-better&quot;&gt;Fewer choices would be better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technological revolution we are living in should give us fewer choices. We should have fewer choices but better options. Technology should make it possible to have the &lt;strong&gt;BEST&lt;/strong&gt; of a thing all wrapped up. Without having to choose between options that we don’t understand. We shouldn’t need an expert to weigh the pros and cons of a purchase that should be straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have clients (&lt;em&gt;and friends&lt;/em&gt;) ask me all the time, what computer should I get? What web hosting company should I use. What e-commerce platform should I have. The problem in giving advice for those things is the myriad of choices within each choice. It is a rabbit hole that they have gone down, gotten lost and confused in, and now are asking for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving customers choice purely to offer lots of choices doesn’t make for happy customers. It makes for confused people who are never satisfied with what they choose.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="technology" /><category term="story" /><summary type="html">I get asked all the time to be the arbiter of technology. People get overwhelmed with the volume of choices out there. And while choice and variety is good, it can sometimes be too much. After all, there is such a thing as too much of a good thing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/too-much-choice.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why You Need A SSL Certificate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/why-you-need-a-ssl-certificate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Need A SSL Certificate" /><published>2017-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/why-you-need-a-ssl-certificate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/why-you-need-a-ssl-certificate/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/ssl-certificates-are-the-future.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SSL Certificate are not as safe as we are told they are.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you all know the internet gods have deemed it necessary for all websites to be secure. This means applying a &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificate&lt;/strong&gt; to your domain. They don’t literally “&lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt;” it but if you don’t have one all the browsers will label your site as “&lt;em&gt;Not having a Secure connection&lt;/em&gt;”. Depending on your device and the security settings this could mean next to nothing or it could block access to your site.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sure-ssl-certificates-are-important-but&quot;&gt;Sure SSL Certificates are Important, But&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are purchasing things online it should always be done through a secure connection. This means having a &lt;strong&gt;HTTPS&lt;/strong&gt; in the address. The padlock icon should be there. But does than mean you are safe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a word, &lt;strong&gt;NO&lt;/strong&gt;. Anyone can get a &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificate&lt;/strong&gt; for a website. Having the &lt;strong&gt;HTTPS&lt;/strong&gt; and the padlock icon only means the site has a certificate. It doesn’t mean the owners of the site are not criminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not that simple. The SSL certificate only means two things. One, that the owner of the site has secured a &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificate&lt;/strong&gt; and that the connection to the site is encrypted. Lets look at the certificate first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-to-get-a-ssl-certificate&quot;&gt;Where to Get a SSL Certificate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSL certificates&lt;/strong&gt; are easy to get. Many &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.godaddy.com/web-security/ssl-certificate&quot;&gt;hosting companies&lt;/a&gt; sell certificates. They are usually not cheap but very easy to install. Many are literally one click installs. Some services sell certificates that you can use on any hosting platform, and other companies give them away for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I host this site through &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. This is a free hosting service. However they do not offer or support &lt;strong&gt;HTTPS&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificates&lt;/strong&gt;. But if you use the &lt;strong&gt;CDN&lt;/strong&gt; service &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com&quot;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt;, you can get a &lt;strong&gt;SSL&lt;/strong&gt; for your GitHub Pages site. They offer a free membership level that includes a &lt;strong&gt;SSL&lt;/strong&gt;. I don’t pay for hosting and I don’t pay for my &lt;strong&gt;SSL&lt;/strong&gt;, but as you can see my site has the padlock icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/my-ssl-padlock-icon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My site has a SSL certificate I got for free.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all certificates are equal though. There are high-end certificates that require verification of the registrar and even a review of the company. These more detailed and expensive &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificates&lt;/strong&gt; can take days and even weeks to get. Usually only large volume online sellers have these. A typical &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificate&lt;/strong&gt; is issued within minutes, if not instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificate&lt;/strong&gt; doesn’t mean the site is safe, or that the site is, and does, what they claim to. It just means the owner of the site has applied a &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificate&lt;/strong&gt; to the site. That is all, nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-encryption&quot;&gt;What About Encryption?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, a site with a &lt;strong&gt;SSL&lt;/strong&gt;, no matter who sold it, or purchased it, is encrypted. This means the communication between you and the site can’t be snooped on. There is a secure connection between you and the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a certificate exchange between your browser and the website. The communication is then encrypted. If anyone tried to see what you were doing, they would only see encrypted data. This is very good for protecting usernames, passwords, personal data, and of course credit card information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-make-this-mandatory&quot;&gt;Why Make This Mandatory?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not going to stop cybercrime. It is not going to stop identity theft either. So why bother? Because as the world turns to the web for, well, everything. It needs to keep evolving. Adding &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificates&lt;/strong&gt; to all websites just makes it harder for criminals. Think of it as locks on your windows. Sure, any criminal can just smash the glass. But the majority will try the window and if it is locked, they will move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To force the use of &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificates&lt;/strong&gt; Google has made changes to its website ranking algorithm. A site without &lt;strong&gt;HTTPS&lt;/strong&gt; will be penalized. In the never ending pig-pile of page rank and &lt;strong&gt;SEO&lt;/strong&gt;, adding a &lt;strong&gt;SSL certificate&lt;/strong&gt; is an easy decision. Add one, become compliant and move forward. That is until the next protective measure becomes mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="help" /><category term="hosting" /><category term="security" /><summary type="html">As you all know the internet gods have deemed it necessary for all websites to be secure. This means applying a SSL certificate to your domain. They don’t literally “require” it but if you don’t have one all the browsers will label your site as “Not having a Secure connection”. Depending on your device and the security settings this could mean next to nothing or it could block access to your site.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/ssl-certificates-are-the-future.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll and Facebook OG Images</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll-and-facebook-og-images/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll and Facebook OG Images" /><published>2017-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-and-facebook-og-images</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll-and-facebook-og-images/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/jekyll-and-facebook-og-images.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jekyll and Facebook OG images&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be very basic stuff but I figured it out and wanted to share it. For me it was not so basic or clear. I did a lot of Googling and could not find the answer. Usually that means it is super simple and no one needs to look up the answer. Except, well, for me.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you have your cool &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; driven, static website blog up and running on GitHub Pages (&lt;em&gt;a really useful free resource&lt;/em&gt;). And you have written a super cool blog post you want to share with the world! However, when you go to post a link on Facebook the main image of the post doesn’t show, what do you do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;every-jekyll-setup-is-different-this-is-what-i-did&quot;&gt;Every &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; setup is different, this is what I did.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook uses the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ogp.me/&quot;&gt;Open Graph protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;OG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) which enables any web page to become a rich object in a social graph. This is used on Facebook to allow any web page to have the same functionality as any other object on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added this code to the head.html file that is located in the “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;_includes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;” folder of my Jekyll setup. This is the Open Graph stuff Facebook uses!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;og:locale&quot; content=&quot;en_US&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;article&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;{% if page.title %}{{ page.title }}{% else %}{{ site.title }}{% endif %}&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;{% if page.description %}{{ page.description }}{% else %}{{ site.description }}{% endif %}&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;{{ site.url }}{{ page.url }}&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;{{ site.title }}&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;{{ site.url }}/images/{{ page.image }}&quot;&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:width&quot; content=&quot;637&quot; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:height&quot; content=&quot;403&quot; /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important part of all that code is the parts about calling the image (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;property=“og:image”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and setting the size. Facebook likes to have a specific size set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-liquid-markup-for-calling-an-image-is&quot;&gt;The liquid markup for calling an image is:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;{{ site.url }}/images/{{ page.image }}&quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have now set up the OG tags in the “&lt;em&gt;head&lt;/em&gt;” but where is it getting the images from? Well you set the image in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/frontmatter/&quot;&gt;YAML front matter&lt;/a&gt; of the post. As you know all Jekyll posts use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yaml.org/&quot;&gt;YAML&lt;/a&gt; (YAML Ain’t Markup Language). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yaml.org/&quot;&gt;YAML&lt;/a&gt; is a human friendly data serialization standard for all programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-is-an-example-of-setting-an-image-in-the-yaml-front-matter&quot;&gt;Here is an example of setting an image in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/frontmatter/&quot;&gt;YAML Front Matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
layout: post
title: 3 Reasons to Switch from WordPress to Jekyll
description: &quot;These are the 3 reasons I switched away from WordPress and to using Jekyll a static website builder.&quot;
modified: 2017-02-18
tags: [jekyll, wordpress]
image: 3-reasons-to-switch-from-wordpress-to-jekyll.jpg
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By adding the “&lt;strong&gt;image:&lt;/strong&gt;*” to the Front Matter you have told Jekyll what image is associated with this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that is about it! You have included in every Page and Post an og:image tag. And you have declared in every Post’s YAML Front Matter what image goes with that Post. Now Facebook has all the data it needs to display your super cool Post along with its Wicked Catchy image.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="facebook" /><category term="Open Graph" /><summary type="html">This might be very basic stuff but I figured it out and wanted to share it. For me it was not so basic or clear. I did a lot of Googling and could not find the answer. Usually that means it is super simple and no one needs to look up the answer. Except, well, for me.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jekyll-and-facebook-og-images.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">3 Reasons to Switch from WordPress to Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-switch-from-wordpress-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 Reasons to Switch from WordPress to Jekyll" /><published>2017-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-switch-from-wordpress-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-switch-from-wordpress-to-jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/3-reasons-to-switch-from-wordpress-to-jekyll.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3 Reasons to Switch from WordPress to Jekyll&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! this is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyl is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; driven static website. I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, but why? There are &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; main reasons I did this. Well &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; reasons really. But the forth reason might not apply to the average person or blogger.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll-is-fast&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is Fast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean by that is &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a static website builder. A static website is much faster than a dynamic one. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; is dynamic, meaning it rides on a database and uses a lot of computing power to generate dynamic pages. In the most basic sense a dynamic page doesn’t exist until someone visits it. At that time &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and the database kick to life and build the page and send it to the visitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dynamic sites have their place, but the reality is most bloggers and websites really don’t need it. In the real world the average person or company isn’t as popular or feature rich as FaceBook, no matter how much we’d like that to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So lets just get the stuff we need and drop the rest. Doing so will speed up the loading of your website. In most cases simpler is faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll-is-simpler&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is Simpler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets be honest, neither &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; nor &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; are really that simple. As with all websites most of the work goes into the initial development. In that area &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; are fairly equal, I would even say &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a bit simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond all the technical &lt;em&gt;crap&lt;/em&gt; the bottom line is once the site is built the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; site is far simpler. There are no plugins to update. There isn’t a &lt;strong&gt;CMS&lt;/strong&gt; to keep up to date. You do not have to deal with an updated plugin that conflicts with the &lt;strong&gt;CMS&lt;/strong&gt;, or another plugin. Or my favorite head ache, the unsupported plugin. Unsupported plugins can send you scrambling for a replacement, they can also be a &lt;strong&gt;huge security risk&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll-is-safer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is Safer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to get overly technical here, but there are &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; main reasons why &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; is not very secure. The first is because it uses server-side scripts, in the &lt;strong&gt;PHP&lt;/strong&gt; language. These use whats called URL parameters to control the database (&lt;em&gt;MySQL&lt;/em&gt;). Hackers can use whats called a &lt;strong&gt;SQL injection attacks&lt;/strong&gt; to get sensitive database information. Once they have that they can hijack the site and change or replace your content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second reason &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; is not secure has to do with themes and plugins. You can get free themes or paid themes, same with plugins. Sometimes these themes or plugins have errors that leave a security hole in your website. Because they are easy to get and install most people will have no idea there is a security problem, the developer might not even know it. Because of the massive number of people using &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; it has become fertile ground for &lt;em&gt;unscrupulous&lt;/em&gt; developers to add malware into their themes and plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-main-problem-with-wordpress-is-you&quot;&gt;The main problem with &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; is You!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last reason I think &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; is not secure is &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt;! And to be fare, me as well. We are human and busy humans at that. It is natural for us to let things get a bit out of date, fall behind, not keep on top of things. This can be a huge problem when dealing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;. Failing to keep &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; up-to-date can leave you vulnerable to attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/life-gets-in-the-way-of-wordpress.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-title=&quot;Image title&quot; data-footer=&quot;Image footer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/life-gets-in-the-way-of-wordpress.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Life is too busy for WordPress&quot; width=&quot;960px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goes back to the simplicity problem. Many people don’t like updating &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; or plugins simply because it can cause problems. More times than I’d like to remember my day, or entire weekend, has been ruined by simply updating &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve done more than a few plugin updates that resulted in the dreaded &lt;strong&gt;White Screen of Death&lt;/strong&gt;. For this reason I only do updates when I know I have a block of time that can be dedicated to fixing any possible problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People try to avoid problems by not updating. This might seem like a reasonable tactic but it is a ticking time bomb. Updates fix security vulnerabilities. It is just a question of time before an out of date &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; website is hacked, not if, but &lt;strong&gt;when&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore a static website, which is just a collection of simple text files, is safer. There is nothing to hijack. There is nothing to take control of. There is nothing to keep updated. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; site can be ignored as much as you want and it won’t hurt you. Its the best type of a site for a busy company or person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any updates or changes doen to a Jekyll site are always done on a development machine (&lt;em&gt;your home PC&lt;/em&gt;) first and not the web server. This allows you to work out any problems before they go live. Sure you could create a local version of your &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; site, but for the average person that is beyond their technical abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll-keeps-me-sharp&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; Keeps Me Sharp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reason for using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; over &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; is very personal and may not apply to everyone. I like doing things manually, I find pleasure in knowing the inner workings of things. I feel I am a better “&lt;em&gt;technologist&lt;/em&gt;” if I keep my hand in things. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; is fine if you prefer a point and click experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bounce around a lot between graphic design, magazine and book publishing, database management, and server management. Because of this I enjoy the break from my daily grind by getting down and dirty with the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I transitioned away from print, beyond it dying, and into the web was because I enjoyed the feeling of using code to create things that look good and actually do things. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; removed a large part of that for me. I found myself spending a lot of time just maintaining the CMS and doing updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There it is, my &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; reasons for using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; over &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;. Oh, wait there is one more, &lt;strong&gt;money&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;control&lt;/strong&gt;, okay that is really two more. Clients can run and change a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;WordPress is a Website CMS&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; site without me. Thats not good for my bottom line. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll is a Static Website Builder&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; site I build for a client will run better, faster, more securely, and the client (&lt;em&gt;most times&lt;/em&gt;) has to come to me to make changes and/or additions. It is a Win-Win for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="wordpress" /><summary type="html">Yes! this is a Jekyll driven static website. I switched to Jekyll, but why? There are 3 main reasons I did this. Well 4 reasons really. But the forth reason might not apply to the average person or blogger.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-switch-from-wordpress-to-jekyll.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Is a Zippo Tech or Art?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/is-a-zippo-tech-or-art/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is a Zippo Tech or Art?" /><published>2017-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/is-a-zippo-tech-or-art</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/is-a-zippo-tech-or-art/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/is-zippo-tech-and-art.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Zippo Lighter is Art &amp;amp; Technology&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can a lighter be considered art or even technology? Why do I like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zippo.com&quot;&gt;Zippo lighter&lt;/a&gt;? Does the drawbacks of a Zippo make it a better lighter?&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Zippo Manufacturing Company&lt;/strong&gt; was founded in 1932 by George G. Blaisdell. The first Zippo lighters hit the stores in 1933. It was very popular with the military. The lighter’s design and materials has not changed, except during war time when materials were scarce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zippo’s sturdy construction and ability to work in harsh weather made it very popular with campers and hikers. This was also a trait the military liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zippo.com&quot;&gt;Zippo lighter&lt;/a&gt; is more than functional, it has an artistic, timeless quality. It has an iconic shape, but more then that, it has an iconic sound. The sound of a Zippo opening, being lit, and then closing is immediately recognizable all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you combine the shape, the sturdy metal feel in your hand along with the unique sounds it makes, mixed with the smell of the lighter fluid, you have a complete visceral experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It goes beyond just art and experience. It is almost timeless. Every part of the Zippo lighter can be replaced. It can be passed down from generation to generation and still remain functional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-like-to-think-of-it-as-the-lighter-of-theseus&quot;&gt;I like to think of it as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ship_of_Theseus&quot;&gt;The Lighter of Theseus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of all of these attributes the Zippo Lighter is more than just a lighter to me. Its a tool, an object of art, and a touch-stone to the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two myself, even though I don’t smoke. Along with a good knife having a working lighter is a must have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/my-zippo-lighters.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-title=&quot;Image title&quot; data-footer=&quot;Image footer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/my-zippo-lighters.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Two Zippo Lighters&quot; width=&quot;960px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is true that a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zippo.com&quot;&gt;Zippo&lt;/a&gt; will run out of fuel after 2 weeks, sometimes maybe 3. This is because the lighter fuel will evaporate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other manufacturers make a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Thunderbird-Vector-Lighter-Insert-Regular/dp/B009Z2GB16/ref=pd_sim_121_2?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=KA26H1VBZVZZF9XSJSCM&quot;&gt;Butane fueled insert&lt;/a&gt;. This eliminates the fuel from evaporating over time. The Butane insert looks and works the same as the original with the wind guard and the flint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Thunderbird-Vector-Lighter-Insert-Regular/dp/B009Z2GB16/ref=pd_sim_121_2?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=KA26H1VBZVZZF9XSJSCM&quot;&gt;Butane insert&lt;/a&gt; is an improvement over the lighter fluid version. But it removes a bit of the charm I think. Part of it’s charm is maintaining the lighter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that are easy and simple sometimes lack something. It takes effort to keep the lighter filled and the wick and flint in good working order. Gratification can come from simple tasks that connect you to the world around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea is carried over to my preference of &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxmint.com&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; over &lt;strong&gt;Mac&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;PC&lt;/strong&gt;. I like working on a computer. Some people just want it to be an appliance. I prefer to get my hands dirty from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/zippo-lighters-outback.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-title=&quot;Image title&quot; data-footer=&quot;Image footer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/zippo-lighters-outback.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two Zippo Lighters in my back yard&quot; width=&quot;960px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting effort into keeping your computer or your lighter in proper working order is good for you, and your soul.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="story" /><category term="linux" /><summary type="html">Can a lighter be considered art or even technology? Why do I like the Zippo lighter? Does the drawbacks of a Zippo make it a better lighter?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/is-zippo-tech-and-art.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Too Old to Use It</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/too-old-to-use-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Too Old to Use It" /><published>2016-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/too-old-to-use-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/too-old-to-use-it/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/too-old-to-use-it.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Too old to use it&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not many of you will recognize this, it is a 2004, Apple Power Mac G5. A Dual 1.8GHz unit with 4GB of RAM, WiFi card, two 500GB hard drives, a NVIDIA GeForce FX 5200 video card, running OS 10.5 Leopard, to be exact. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is sad because even today it boots quickly and runs smoothly, but is so out of date it is next to useless. This was the first Mac I ever purchased. In today’s dollars I paid about &lt;strong&gt;$2100&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/power-mac-g5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Apple Poer Mac G5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not a top of the line unit, however over the years I added more RAM, a new video card, more hard drives, and a WiFi card. The ability to do these upgrades kept this Mac as a daily driver until 2011. Seven years is a long time, in computer years. You can’t upgrade a modern Mac like that anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/leopard-apple-g5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Apple OX 01.5 Leopard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This machine was a daily driver. It allowed me to make extra money by doing side jobs on it. Upgrading it was a great way to learn with the added benefit of making it better, faster, and more versatile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-is-why-i-cant-seem-to-let-this-hunk-of-aluminum-and-plastic-go&quot;&gt;This is why I can’t seem to let this hunk of aluminum and plastic go.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few times a year I plug it in and lament over how well she runs. Then, I put her back in cold-storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems wrong to throw away (&lt;em&gt;or recycle&lt;/em&gt;) something that works so well. Even if it is kind of useless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="story" /><category term="mac" /><category term="apple" /><summary type="html">Not many of you will recognize this, it is a 2004, Apple Power Mac G5. A Dual 1.8GHz unit with 4GB of RAM, WiFi card, two 500GB hard drives, a NVIDIA GeForce FX 5200 video card, running OS 10.5 Leopard, to be exact.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/too-old-to-use-it.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Data is an Echo of You</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/data-is-an-echo-of-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data is an Echo of You" /><published>2016-12-16T02:57:32-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-16T02:57:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/data-is-an-echo-of-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/data-is-an-echo-of-you/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/data-is-an-echo-of-you.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Data is an Echo of You&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will I be remembered? How much of what I do, and how I do it, will carry an invisible description of who I am? More importantly, how did an old database get me thinking about all this stuff?&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was tasked with bringing an old &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Access&lt;/strong&gt; database into the 21st century. This database had been the heart of a business for almost two decades. But for the last &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; years it had sat mostly unused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving a Windows based database over to Mac is not super simple. It is not the hardest thing in the world either. It did force me to abandon my compulsion to “fix” everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the data was now accessed very infrequently there was no need to bring it up to todays standards, structure wise. It was not going to be an active part of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used an application called &lt;a href=&quot;https://eggerapps.at/mdbviewer/&quot;&gt;MDB ACCDB Viewer&lt;/a&gt;, available through the &lt;strong&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;$19&lt;/strong&gt;. This gave me easy access to the Access database’s tables. I then exported the tables I needed in CSV format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/filemaker-edit-layout.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FileMaker edit layout mode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there I used FileMaker to recreate the database, at least the parts I needed. Linking the tables and building the layouts and the scripts was nothing special. I did have a bit of a struggle with a printing script, but thats a story for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/table-relationships.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FileMaker table relation graph&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.filemaker.com&quot;&gt;Filemaker database&lt;/a&gt; was finished I had to test it. I did all kinds of searching and filtering of the data. I had to return to the old data a few times to grab some more tables to make the new system a bit more flushed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you filter through orders going as far back as &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt; you can see people. In the beginning the orders were very detailed, every box was ticked, every data field was populated. Then there was a gradual change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I moved through the files, traveling forward in time, I could see someone else was entering orders. They were far less detailed orientated. The orders and customer information became far less descriptive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-entry-decay&quot;&gt;Data Entry Decay?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like watching a tire coming apart as a truck speeds down a highway, I could see the inevitable. The change to the next person entering data was abrupt. A new style, not as bad as the last but not as good as the first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was clear there was an attempt made to be thorough and complete. By looking at the orders and the notes sections I got the sense of someone struggling. Is it even possible to get a sense of a person’s day to day life simply by how they entered data?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I went through my testing the years flew past. Sales data of good months and bad months, good seasons and bad seasons seemed compressed into waves I could almost hear, like a far off beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to have feelings of hostility towards the people that did a very poor job of entering data. It complicated the task of testing the database. I could not simply test the system, I had to verify poor results as either a structure problem or inaccurate data entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-it-the-data-or-is-it-me&quot;&gt;Is it the Data, Or is it Me?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point I was convinced my new system was fatally flawed. Then I realized I was testing a section of the data that was populated by someone who clearly didn’t like their job. It would be fair to say, whoever they were, they went out of their way to do a poor job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got me thinking about how I will be judged in the future. My previous careers left no chance of people in the future critiquing my work. Driving a truck is a “in the moment” type of a thing. You can’t look back, thirty years from now and review, in detail how 18 yards of concrete was delivered. (Spoiler - it was delivered expertly)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in the digital field I do work that could easily still be around, in some form or another 30, 50, maybe 70 years from now. It is not just people who work in the I.T. field either. Stuff on Facebook and YouTube could be here for many life times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I approached the current time-line, in my database testing, I softened by attitude towards the people who worked in the old system. I was struck by how much of a person could to be imprinted into such a cold medium as a database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-thought-for-the-future&quot;&gt;A Thought for the Future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no way for me to tell those people I felt their echo, a small vibration of their existence recorded in an obscure data entry system. And I wonder if anything I do today will be felt by someone decades from now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that if someone in the future is struggling with something I have worked on, or with, that they can feel my desire to do it correctly. It would be nice if they could tell I liked what I did, and I tried to do it with care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe this was all in my head. Maybe it is just a database, a collection of numbers and letters in little boxes that can’t record anything about its user. But, I hope not.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How will I be remembered? How much of what I do, and how I do it, will carry an invisible description of who I am? More importantly, how did an old database get me thinking about all this stuff?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/data-is-an-echo-of-you.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Migrating from WordPress to Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/migrate-from-wordpress-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrating from WordPress to Jekyll" /><published>2016-09-23T02:57:32-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-23T02:57:32-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/migrate-from-wordpress-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/migrate-from-wordpress-to-jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/migrate-from-wordpress-to-jekyll.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;moving from WordPress to Jekyll&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you want to migrate from &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It can be easy or a huge pain in the ass. Well, when it comes to dealing with Jekyll it is never apple pie simple. But every time you use it you do learn something. I find learning as you go to be more important than just a simple point-and-click experience.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to migrate from WordPress to &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and you want to bring in all your old Posts and Pages, this is what you need to do. You need to get your WordPress database, install it on a local MySQL database, then migrate it from that database to Jekyll. Simple, there you go, thank you for reading this post! Bye!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish it was that simple. I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://godaddy.com&quot;&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/a&gt; for hosting and they have cPanel which is good. Log into whatever control panel you have, go to the &lt;strong&gt;phpMyAdmin&lt;/strong&gt;. When in &lt;strong&gt;phpMyAdmin&lt;/strong&gt; find your database, click on it and click the “&lt;em&gt;Export&lt;/em&gt;” tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/cPanel-and-phpMyAdmin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cPanel in phpMyAdmin&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;cPanel locate phpMyAmin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Export screen is super simple. Just leave all the settings alone and click the Go button. It will download the database as an SQL file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/export-your-wordpress-database.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Export your data&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Export your data&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should install &lt;a href=&quot;https://mamp.info&quot;&gt;MAMP&lt;/a&gt;, it will run on a Windows, Linux or Mac system, I use a Mac. Once &lt;a href=&quot;https://mamp.info&quot;&gt;MAMP&lt;/a&gt; is installed and running, you want to go to phpMyAdmin and create a database. Once it is created, click the “Import” tab. Click the “&lt;strong&gt;Choose File&lt;/strong&gt;” button then navigate to the SQL file you downloaded from you hosting account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/create-a-new-database.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;create a database in phpmyadmimn&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Create a Database&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/import-wordpress-data.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;import the wordpress data&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Import the WordPress data&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;migrate-from-wordpress--now-for-jekyll&quot;&gt;Migrate from WordPress – Now for Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am assuming you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; installed and you have created a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; project. After that is done you should have a folder that looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/default-jekyll-project-folder.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;default Jekyll folder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default Jekyll website looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/default-jekyl-website.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Migrating from WordPress - Jekyll default website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default theme that &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; uses (at the time this was written) is called Minima. I found it helpful to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/minima&quot;&gt;download the Minima theme&lt;/a&gt; so you have the default files to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/minima-folder-files.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;minima-folder-files&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it is time to import the data from your local &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; database. This can be tricky and you can run into some problems. I have done this before without any issues. Then when I try and do it a week later I have nothing but issues. It is important to stay calm and work the problem and not get frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, this last time I had to add the following to the Gemfile. I didn’t have to do this the last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gem &quot;sequel&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gem &quot;unidecode&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gemfile-and-added-gems.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;migrating from WordPress to Jekyll&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also ran into a problem with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; import. I had to install it using this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$ gem install jekyll-import&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not the end either. I had to install the following in order to get Ruby to connect to the database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gem install mysql2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connecting to the database was another issue. If you are using MAMP the “&lt;em&gt;Path&lt;/em&gt;” is very specific and something I struggled with. The Path you want to use it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1
/Applications/MAMP/tmp/mysql/mysql.sock
The import code you enter in the command line is posted on the Jekyll website in the migration section. Below is what I used, remember you will need to put in your own database name, user, and password. This is the code I used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ruby -rubygems -e 'require &quot;jekyll-import&quot;;
    JekyllImport::Importers::WordPress.run({
      &quot;dbname&quot;   =&amp;gt; &quot;group-1&quot;,
      &quot;user&quot;     =&amp;gt; &quot;root&quot;,
      &quot;password&quot; =&amp;gt; &quot;root&quot;,
      &quot;host&quot;     =&amp;gt; &quot;localhost&quot;,
      &quot;socket&quot;   =&amp;gt; &quot;/Applications/MAMP/tmp/mysql/mysql.sock&quot;,
      &quot;table_prefix&quot;   =&amp;gt; &quot;wp_&quot;,
      &quot;site_prefix&quot;    =&amp;gt; &quot;&quot;,
      &quot;clean_entities&quot; =&amp;gt; true,
      &quot;comments&quot;       =&amp;gt; true,
      &quot;categories&quot;     =&amp;gt; true,
      &quot;tags&quot;           =&amp;gt; true,
      &quot;more_excerpt&quot;   =&amp;gt; true,
      &quot;more_anchor&quot;    =&amp;gt; true,
      &quot;extension&quot;      =&amp;gt; &quot;html&quot;,
      &quot;status&quot;         =&amp;gt; [&quot;publish&quot;]
    })'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;migration-is-not-100-perfect&quot;&gt;Migration is not 100% Perfect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully if you migrate from &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; it will go smoothly. I said before, if you get errors work them. Copy and paste them in Google, read what other people did to fix the issues. It is not that difficult to figure out, I did and so can you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result will be a horrible looking website. But that is what you get when you migrate from &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;. This is what my site looked like after the migration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/website-after-wordpress-migration.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;migrate from WordPress website-after-wordpress-migration&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does require a lot of clean-up and moving of images. But it does a lot of the heavy lifting up front. It might look messy but it gives you a jumping off point. You now have all the content from your &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; site in &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just want to remind people that I am still learning. I do not know all the tricks. I am just putting this out there for people like me. I believe that it is important to share your knowledge and help other people. Everyday in my journey of learning I am thankful for the countless people out there that are willing to share what they know. I hope this helps someone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="help" /><category term="jekyll" /><summary type="html">So, you want to migrate from WordPress to Jekyll. It can be easy or a huge pain in the ass. Well, when it comes to dealing with Jekyll it is never apple pie simple. But every time you use it you do learn something. I find learning as you go to be more important than just a simple point-and-click experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/migrate-from-wordpress-to-jekyll.jpg" /></entry></feed>